hey welcome back
嘿 欢迎回来
it's been a while i know
我知道已经有一段时间了
before we start i want to present you
在我们开始之前 我想向大家介绍一下
with a little experiment
通过一个小小的实验
let's split this canvas in two
让我们把这块画布一分为二
i'll paint one side with
我要用来画一面
80 blue
80蓝色
and i'll paint the other side
然后我来画另一边
with 80 blue and 1 green
80个蓝色和1个绿色
and we can merge these two
我们可以把这两者合并起来
and i'll delete the bottom two layers
我会删除最下面的两层
okay hide the line
好的 把线藏起来
now these two colors
现在这两种颜色
are almost indistinguishable to the
几乎无法区分
naked eye i'll apply an exposure filter
肉眼我会涂上曝光滤光片
and what do you think is going to happen
你认为会发生什么？
when i push this slider all the way to
当我把这个滑块一直推到
the right
权利
this is going to be a the image will
这将是一个形象将
become very blue and stop changing b the
变得非常忧郁 不要再换衣服了
image will become white and stop
图像将变为白色并停止
changing
正在改变
or c the image will turn to
或c 则图像将变为
correct
对 是这样
the image turned to
图像变成了
it makes no sense whatsoever for these
对于这些人来说 这是毫无意义的
two formerly indistinguishable colors to
以前难以区分的两种颜色
become so different after we increase
在我们增加之后变得如此不同
the exposure
曝光率
i can 100 guarantee that you've already
我可以百分百保证你已经
seen this kind of scion in digital
在数字时代看到了这种接班人
photography
摄影术
especially in your usual day-to-day
尤其是在你平常的日常生活中
smartphone photos
智能手机照片
the gradient of the sky goes from nice
天空的坡度从很好的
dark blue to lighter blue then breaks
从深蓝色到浅蓝色 然后破裂
into cyan and eventually turns white
变成青色 最终变成白色
this is called a hue shift and it's
这被称为色调变化 它是
prominent everywhere the sky the sun
到处都是太阳和天空
even yourself is in room lighting you
甚至你自己也在房间里照亮你
can even notice it in some 3d animation
我甚至可以在一些3D动画中注意到它
renders
渲染
here's an exaggerated example with a 3d
这里有一个夸张的3D示例
watch the background sky blue turn into
看着背景天空的蓝色变成
cyan and the orangey brown scare turn
青色和橙色惊吓转身
into yellow hue shifts are all over the
变成黄色色调的变化到处都是
place so what would be the expected
地点 那么预计会是什么呢？
result the image should turn to white as
结果图像应该变成白色 因为
i increase the exposure just like it
我就像这样增加曝光率
does for example in dark table using the
例如 在暗表中使用
filmic rgb module
胶片RGB模块
it makes sense that the minute
这是有道理的 那一刻
differences between the two colors is
这两种颜色之间的差异是
kept
保留
and it only makes sense that substantial
它只有那么重要才说得通
overexposure leads to completely wide
过度暴露会导致完全广泛的
image the people who engineered film
想象一下设计电影的人
photography knew it even the painters of
摄影知道这一点 即使是画家
renaissance knew it but somehow digital
文艺复兴知道这一点 但不知何故数字化了
color came and we forgot
颜色来了 我们都忘了
thankfully this bad image formation has
谢天谢地 这种不良形象的形成
awoken a bunch of smart angry people who
唤醒了一群聪明的愤怒的人
had enough knowledge and skill to try
有足够的知识和技能去尝试
and fix that awful imagery we're
修复我们可怕的形象
bombarded with daily now it's up to us
被《每日报》轰炸 现在就看我们的了
to use the tools and recognize
使用这些工具并认识到
and point out the terrible things that
并指出那些可怕的事情
are done to imagery
都是对意象做的
remember the ugly 3d render
还记得难看的3D渲染吗
well now let's watch the filmic render
好了 现在让我们来看电影渲染
side by side with our earlier render
与我们早期的渲染并排
same scene but the outcome looks much
同样的场景 但结果看起来很像
nicer and much more natural almost like
更好更自然 几乎就像
a painting almost film-like even popular
一幅几乎像电影一样甚至很受欢迎的画
software like adobe lightroom does this
像adobe Lightroom这样的软件就是这样做的
to an extent
在某种程度上
of course i have no control over it but
当然我控制不了它 但是
it's there somewhere
它就在那里的某个地方
hold on you might say irish to you just
等一下 你可能会对你说爱尔兰话
talking about display referred and scene
浅谈展示参照与场景
referred workflows yes and no
参考的工作流是和否
but i don't want to get into that in
但我不想深入到这一点
this video as this will need a video
这个视频需要一个视频
rant of its own
它自己的咆哮
the terminology is really fuzzy right
术语很模糊 对吧？
now while it settles it's best that we
现在事情解决了 我们最好还是
focus on the image and the result it's
把注意力集中在图像和结果上
the image that is of utmost importance
最重要的形象
to us and the viewer
给我们和观众
just keep in mind that photography is
只要记住 摄影是
art and don't limit yourself by trying
艺术 不要通过尝试来限制自己
to replicate the real world in your
在您的计算机中复制真实世界
photos it's not possible and probably
照片是不可能的 而且很可能
never will be
永远不会是
great images that are excellent
极好的图像
beautiful interesting as an object on
作为一件物品很漂亮 很有趣
its own
它自己的
not some sort of 2d bargain bin
不是什么2D的便宜货
representation of the real world
真实世界的再现
you know what's not an image data
你知道什么不是图像数据吗
data you capture with your digital
您使用数字设备捕获的数据
camera that data is not an image until
摄像机数据不是图像 直到
we develop it and turn it into an image
我们把它冲洗出来 然后把它变成一个形象
until we touch it it's just a bunch of
直到我们触摸到它 它只是一堆
sensor readouts
传感器读数
people call them raw images but i'm not
人们称它们为原始图像 但我不是
the fan of that name either
这个名字的粉丝要么
camera native data capture file is a
摄像机本机数据捕获文件是
mouthful but it represents that raw
很有口感 但它代表着生的
files are different from camera to
不同摄像机的文件不同
camera
摄像机
and most importantly it recognizes that
最重要的是 它认识到
the data capture is not an image
数据捕获不是图像
i'm just going to call it scene this
我就叫它这一幕吧
just kidding we'll figure something out
开个玩笑 我们会想出办法的
as we go
当我们走的时候
so how do we turn not an image into an
那么 我们如何将不是一个图像变成一个
image
图像
we use tools good modern tools that help
我们使用工具好的现代工具来帮助
us form the image in the way that it's
我们塑造形象的方式是
intuitive and most importantly makes
直观 最重要的是使
sense dark tables filmic rgb is one of
感光暗桌电影RGB是其中之一
those tools
那些工具
the filmic rgb module in dark table was
暗桌中的胶片RGB模块是
created by aurelion pierre who was
由奥瑞安·皮埃尔创作 他是
inspired by troy stobotka the person who
在特洛伊·斯托博特卡的启发下
made filmic for blender the idea of the
为搅拌机拍摄电影的想法
whole filmic thing is that it mimics
整个电影的事情就是模仿
film in both highlight and shadow
高光和阴影中的电影
desaturation as well as beautiful
去饱和度和美观一样
highlight and shadow roll-offs
高光和阴影滚动
avoiding hue shifts as much as possible
尽可能避免色调变化
basically it is a view transform it
从根本上说 它是一种视图 变换它
takes the data captured by a camera and
把摄像机捕捉到的数据
forms an image that your monitor is able
形成显示器能够显示的图像
to display with the help of a few
在几个人的帮助下展示
modules
模块
and your input
以及您的意见
that way we avoid the issue that was
这样一来 我们就避免了
shown at the beginning of the video we
在视频的开头我们展示了
can avoid hue shifts both sterilization
可以避免色调变化和杀菌
and other unpredicted distortions that
以及其他出乎意料的扭曲
ruin our picture
毁了我们的照片
let's have a better look at what is
让我们更好地看看是什么
going on
正在进行中
i have dark table opened where i have a
我开了一张暗桌 我有一张
bunch of test images that help us limit
一组测试图像 帮助我们限制
test and better visualize the changes to
测试并更好地可视化更改
our photos
我们的照片
you can already see that we're
你已经看到了 我们正在
encountering the same issue we've
遇到了我们遇到的同样的问题
encountered at the beginning of the
在开始时遇到的
video
视频
the ugly broken blue
丑陋的破碎的蓝色
has turned into cyan and is ruining our
已经变成了青色 正在毁掉我们的
landscape
景观
let's fix that by simply enabling the
让我们通过简单地启用
filmic rgb module
胶片RGB模块
notice how the blue
注意蓝色是如何
just transitions to white
只是过渡到白色
without any hue shift whatsoever there's
没有任何色调变化
no scion there's no posterization
没有子孙 没有色调
there's no
没有
clipped highlights below the sun
剪裁的阳光下的高光
everything's nice and smooth
一切都很好很顺利
similarly the same issue can be seen in
同样 同样的问题也可以在
sunsets
日落
the red orange sunset can turn into ugly
红色的橙色落日会变成丑陋的
yellow really quickly
很快就变黄了
this is also a hue shift and it's
这也是一种色调变化 它是
something filmic can fix
一些电影可以修复的东西
there we go much better
我们现在做得好多了
we can compare these two side by side
我们可以把这两个并排比较一下
look at the difference
看看它们的区别
this looks harsh
这看起来很刺耳
overcooked and almost deep fried
煮过头了 几乎是油炸的
whereas this feels natural and smooth
虽然这感觉很自然和顺畅
first of all let's get familiar with
首先让我们来熟悉一下
filmic rgb
电影RGB
there are a few buttons that will help
有几个按钮会有帮助
us better understand how it all works
我们更好地了解这一切是如何运作的
the a button turns the axis labels on
A按钮打开轴标签
that helps us immensely
这对我们有很大的帮助
and the rotate button switches between
旋转按钮在
different modes of graphs that show us
不同模式的图表向我们展示
what filmic rgb is doing
电影RGB正在做什么
let's settle on the first one that's
让我们来决定第一个是
called look only that's what we care
这就是我们所关心的
about the most right now
关于现在最多的
the orange dot somewhere in the middle
中间某个橙色的圆点
indicates the middle gray point notice
表示中间的灰点通知
that the middle gray of your capture
你被俘的中间灰色
is mapped to
映射到
of the display's luminance
显示器的亮度
why not 50
为什么不是50个
you might ask
你可能会问
because humans perceive lightness in a
因为人类在一种
non-linear way this is where we mix some
非线性的方式 这就是我们混合一些
biology into physics
生物学走进物理学
we humans are quite a bit more sensitive
我们人类要敏感得多
to changes in dark tones compared to the
到暗色调的变化 与
same incremental changes in bright tones
明亮色调中的相同增量变化
here's a very awful example
这是一个非常糟糕的例子
at home your room is illuminated by what
在家里 你的房间是由什么照明的
one or two lights but at the office you
一两盏灯 但在办公室里你
have a raisin array of lights when they
有葡萄干的灯光阵列 当他们
don't feel that much brighter than the
别觉得自己比你的
feeling in the room while the change
换衣服时在房间里的感觉
between one two and three lights feel
在一个、两个和三个灯光之间感觉
massive a change between 20 21 or 22
20、21或22之间的巨大变化
lights feel minuscule even though we're
灯光感觉微不足道 即使我们
adding the same amount of light
添加相同数量的光
the 18 of luminance of the leads in your
您的导线亮度的18%
display become an on-screen color picker
显示器成为屏幕上的颜色选择器
value of 0.5
值为0.5
in perfect conditions of course the
当然 在完美的条件下
middle gray point is set and adjusted
设置并调整中间灰点
when you adjust the exposure in the
当您在
exposure module
曝光模块
if you have a lot of dark tones in your
如果你的电脑里有很多黑色的色调
image
图像
that you want to be visible the balance
你想让天平看得见
might look off
可能会看起来很别扭
but it's perfectly normal as the grade
但这很正常 因为年级
point of zero ev of the capture is
捕获的零点EV是
always pinned to the eighteen percent of
总是被固定在18%的
luminance of the display
显示器的亮度
the middle gray or neutral gray has that
中灰色或中性灰色就有这一点
name for a reason
取名是有原因的
in ideal conditions it stays neutral
在理想情况下 它保持中性
it does not obtain chroma or saturation
它不能获得色度或饱和度
and it does not get brighter dimmer when
它不会变得更亮更暗
you adjust the contrast
你可以调整对比度
until a certain point in your image
直到您的图像中的某个点
making pipeline of course
当然是制造管道
what else can we see in this graph
在这张图中我们还能看到什么？
well the main subject is this white
好的 主要的主题是这个白色的
s-curve
S-曲线
values from the camera file are mapped
映射相机文件中的值
to the display according to the curve
根据曲线显示到显示器
lowest brightness values in the capture
截图中的最低亮度值
will get pinned to the lowest luminance
将固定到最低亮度
of your display
您的显示器的
the highest values of your captcha will
你的验证码的最高价值将
be mapped to maximum luminance of your
映射到您的最大亮度
display
显示
it's in your control where you set these
它在你的控制下 在哪里你设置这些
points using black and white relative
使用黑白相对点
exposure
暴露
see these numbers change
请看这些数字的变化
these s bands
这些S乐队
provide smooth transitions between
在以下方面提供平稳过渡
shadows and mid-tones
阴影和中间色调
then mid-tones and highlights that way
然后以这种方式进行中间色调和高亮显示
we avoid clipping in post and the
我们避免在POST和
dreaded u shifts
令人畏惧的换挡
lastly there's this gray line which
最后是这条灰线
indicates saturation
表示饱和
this is also mimicking how film behaves
这也是在模仿电影的表现
the more you expose the film
你曝光的胶片越多
the brighter and less saturated it gets
它变得越明亮 越不饱和
same in the dark areas
在黑暗的区域也是如此
the darker it gets the less saturated it
天气越暗 饱和程度就越低
becomes
vbl.成为
this alone is an incredible feature of
仅这一点就是一个令人难以置信的功能
the tool as it saves all those pretty
工具 因为它保存了所有漂亮的
sunsets of ours
我们的夕阳
not only sunsets but the bright objects
不仅是日落 还有明亮的物体
that usually get the gaudy digital look
通常会得到花哨的数字外观
as it fails to lose saturation with
因为它不会失去饱和度
intensity
强度
this curve will not be present in later
此曲线将不会出现在稍后的
darkroom iterations
暗室迭代
but i think it's important and it's good
但我认为这很重要 也很好
to know what it does and how it
要知道它做了什么以及它是如何
interacts with the image
与图像交互
desaturation feels very natural as it's
去饱和度感觉非常自然 因为它
the best way to convey brightness in my
传递我的智慧的最好方式
opinion if you look at this extreme
如果你看这个极端的观点
example you will notice that the light
例如 你会注意到灯光
sword illuminates the character
剑照亮人物
but the character looks completely flat
但这个角色看起来完全平淡
especially in this area
尤其是在这一地区
now if we desaturate that area using
现在如果我们用来降低该区域的饱和度
filmic rgb
电影RGB
we will actually get some information
我们实际上会得到一些信息
back that we can understand
回到我们可以理解的地方
it's still perfectly clear that the
仍然非常清楚的是
light sword is red and it emits red
光剑是红色的 它发出红色
light that is very strong even if some
光是很强的 即使有些
parts of this figurine are less red and
这个小雕像的某些部分不那么红
more white
更白
and this exactly is the secret sauce of
而这恰恰是
filmic and filmic rgb the red sword is
电影和电影rgb红色的剑
an excellent extreme example but these
一个很好的极端例子 但这些
things happen to us every day everywhere
我们每天都在发生一些事情
sunsets skies lamps christmas lights
日落天空灯圣诞灯
incoming light through a window from
入射光穿过窗户
outside
外面
fire foreheads reflections the list
火额头反射名单
never ends
永远不会结束
it's time for this grotesque mockery of
现在是时候对这个
photography to end let's move forward
摄影结束让我们继续前进
somewhere where everything doesn't look
一个看起来并不像
like a deep-fried nuclear apocalypse
就像一个油炸的核灾难
that's a lot of information to process
要处理很多信息
for one time we'll finish examining the
我们先检查一下
filmic rgb module in part two of the
电影rgb模块的第二部分
series where i shake my fist at the sky
我在天空摇拳头
some more don't forget to check out the
更多的人不要忘了检查一下
links in the description if you want
如果需要 请在描述中添加链接
more information on this topic
有关此主题的更多信息
thanks for watching i hope you learned
感谢您的收看 希望您能学到
something new today
今天有新的东西
see you soon
很快见到你
bye
再见